Date of birth: 15th February 1982

Nationality: French

ORCID: 0000-0001-9006-8436

NIH BioSketch

Github organization: https://github.com/IARCbioinfo

Website: http://rarecancersgenomics.com

Rare Cancers Genomics Team Genomic Epidemiology Branch International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO)

> 25 avenue Tony Garnier, 69007 Lyon, France Email: follm@iarc.who.int

Research Group: https://www.iarc.who.int/teams-rcg/

Professional Appointments

2021-on	Team Leader, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), Lyon, France
2014-2020	Scientist, International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), Lyon, France
2012-2014	Staff Research Scientist, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Lausanne, Switzerland
2007-2012	Postdoctoral Researcher, Institute of Ecology and Evolution, University of Berne, Switzerland

Honors and awards

2024-on	Member of the WHO classification of turmours 6 th edition subcommittee on								
	computational pathology , International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO), https://tumourclassification.iarc.who.int/								
2023	Young investigator award, International Mesothelioma Interest Group (iMig), https://imig.org								
2022-on	Chair of the of the Rare Cancers Working Group, European Prospective Investigation into Cancer and Nutrition (EPIC), http://epic.iarc.who.int								
2021-on	lung NET task force member, European NEuroendocrine Tumors Society (ENETS), https://www.enets.org								
2016-on	Scientific Committee member, French MESOBANK (virtual mesothelioma national biobank), https://www.netmeso.fr/netmeso/mesopath-et-mesobank								

Education

2004-2007	PhD	in	Population	Genetics	and	Evolution,	University	of	Grenoble,	France.
	https:/	/these	s hal science/te	1-00216192/						

2001–2004 **MSc Computer science and Applied Mathematics, specialization in Bioinformatics**, Grenoble Institute of Technology ENSIMAG, Grenoble, France.

Personal Statement

After studying applied mathematics and computer science, I completed a Ph.D. in population genetics and bioinformatics in 2007. During this time I gained a strong expertise in statistical genetics and bioinformatics methods, and I wrote several software now widely used in the field. After my PhD., I moved to the University of Berne as a postdoctoral researcher where I started to work more specifically on large human genomic data. I developed in particular several Bayesian models to identify genetic variants associated with phenotypes observed in different human populations or ethnic groups, being the consequence of local adaptation. In 2012, I was recruited as a Staff Research Scientist in the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology of Lausanne where I worked on new statistical and bioinformatics methods for the analysis Next Generation Sequencing data. In 2014 I been recruited as a staff scientist to develop computation cancer genomics projects and to coordinate the bioinformatics efforts in the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC-WHO). I am particularly involved in the molecular characterisation of rare thoracic tumors like lung neuroendocrine tumors and malignant mesothelioma, and since 2021 I am co-leading the IARC Rare Cancers Genomics team together with Dr. Lynnette Fernandez-Cuesta.

Publications

77 publications in international peer-reviewed scientific journals, including 9 publications as first/co-first author, and 14 publications as last/co-last/corresponding author.

13'415 total citations, h-index: 42 (source: Google Scholar)

Full list available at Google Scholar and My NCBI Bibliography.